Let's skip training today.
You were hurt pretty badly.
No, my injuries pose no problem.
I am more concerned about
you, Shirou. Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm okay.
If you are in pain, do
not hesitate to speak up.
Sure.
In the face of absolute despair
That nearly burned
our hearts away
You still found the
courage to smile
Like you accepted it all
I lost my voice
And the things I wanted to say
But every time I
fell to my knees
I stood up and kept walking
We were looking for
the ideal white future
Our one and only hope
Now I may be left with nothing
But these raging
emotions that have
Nowhere to go
Still, I'll look for a new dawn
With more than one right answer
I won't stop
Until I find it
A Visitor Approaches Lightly
That's a relief.
The pain is gone.
Yesterday was
pretty rough, I guess.
I think I'll make
breakfast as thanks.
Shirou?
So, Kuzuki-sensei
has called in sick today.
Seriously? Kuzuki-sensei?
Did Hell freeze over?
Sweet! Study hall!
Settle down, everyone.
I know that normally this
is your world history class,
but now that I'm here, let's
have an English pop quiz!
No quizzes!
Tyrant!
Tiger!
Shut up!
If I make last period on Saturday
study hall, it might as well be playtime!
So graciously accept
your teacher's kindness!
School has now ended.
Students are not permitted to
remain on campus after school hours.
Please return home at once.
Should I be worried?
I'm not feeling any pain, but
my arm feels heavier somehow.
I forgot to talk to Tohsaka.
Well, if she didn't come to me, I doubt
there were any major developments.
Sorry I'm home late.
I'll have lunch
ready in a minute.
Shirou?
That's the first time
I've ever broken a dish.
Sorry. I'll clean
it up right away.
Don't worry about
it. Just sit at the table.
You must be fatigued, Shirou.
It's all right. I
will clean it up.
Yeah, maybe I am. Thanks.
All right!
Coming!
T-Tohsaka? What
are you doing here?
I'm here because you stood
me up at our regular check-in.
Stood you up?
Okay, I admit that I
forgot to meet you.
But when did we ever
decide on regular check-ins?
Sorry! I'm sorry for forgetting!
You're right. As partners,
we should check in regularly.
Let's use this opportunity to
hold our meeting here today.
Hang on! We were
just about to have lunch!
Perfect timing, then.
I haven't had lunch yet,
so I'll join you.
Hey! Not so fast!
So in the end, our only option
against Caster is to attack her head-on.
I believe so.
There is a powerful
barrier against spiritual
beings erected
around that mountain.
The front gate is the only way.
So if we force our way in to the
temple grounds, Caster will be waiting.
I suppose so.
Wait, why are you
sitting so far away?
Because you stole
my usual place!
Anyway, once we're on the grounds,
the question is how we'll corner Caster.
Worst case scenario, she might
take out all of Ryuudou Temple.
True, that is something
Caster could do.
Saber, don't say scary
stuff like that so casually!
Are you saying that Caster will
self-destruct if we corner her?
It's likely, yes.
I believe she would.
You two are totally in sync.
Wow, when did it get this late?
I guess we should
wrap things up.
I need to get dinner started.
What is it, Emiya-kun?
Why are you staring at me?
No, I was just...
Oh, I get it.
In public, we're fellow Masters,
so I don't bother you there,
but inside your own home,
you revert to your
natural instincts.
I'm a guy, so it's a
perfectly ordinary reaction.
But don't you
think it's strange?
I mean, Saber's a girl.
And from what I hear, Fujimura-sensei
and Sakura are always coming over.
I shouldn't be any different.
Look, just go home, okay?
Oh? How can I go home when
we've yet to settle on a strategy?
Shirou, Rin's point
is valid, is it not?
I see no issue with
her staying here.
Don't you start too.
All right, fine.
But Fuji-nee—Fujimura-sensei
will probably show up later,
so if anything, you should
worry about convincing her.
I know, I know.
I was aware I'd
have to deal with
Fujimura-sensei from
the start. It'll be fine.
Well, don't blame me if
this blows up in your face.
I'm home!
Welcome back.
Boy, it's cold!
I think it's gonna snow!
Ah, you're making hot pot!
That's my Shirou!
You're freezing!
You always know just what to do!
Be careful!
I'm working over a fire here!
Whatever! Hurry, hurry, hurry!
Hot pot! Hot pot! Hot pot!
Come on, get off me!
I hope you don't mind my
joining you, Fujimura-sensei.
Why, it's Tohsaka-san!
It's rare to see you
at Shirou's—hang on.
What's Tohsaka doing here?
Hang on, Tohsaka-san!
What are you doing
here at this hour?
Don't you have any common sense?
What am I doing here?
I'm being treated to
dinner at Emiya-kun's place.
I think it takes even less
common sense for you to barge
in without even ringing the
doorbell, wouldn't you say?
I-I'm the household chaperone!
Emiya-kun's father
left me in charge,
so I'm basically
part of the family!
Oh, I see.
Emiya-kun and I will be
studying for a test after dinner,
so don't mind us.
Ouch...
Shirou? I mean, Emiya-kun!
What's the meaning of this?
Don't force yourself to use his
surname if you're not used to it.
What you call Emiya-kun
is none of my concern.
Tohsaka-san, did you hear
about this from Sakura-chan?
Who knows?
Unfortunately, anything that Matou-san
told me must be treated as confidential.
But I hope it's
exactly as you think.
Game, set, and match.
I'll leave these here.
Oh, thanks.
Shall I do the dishes?
It wouldn't be fair for me to eat your
food without lifting a finger to help.
Nah. You can just
owe me for next time.
Fujimura-sensei, is
Emiya-kun always this clumsy?
No way.
He's never broken a dish before
for as long as I can remember.
He's probably self-conscious
because you're here.
As in, he's thrown off by
the unexpected intrusion.
Emiya-kun.
I'll take it from here,
so go get some rest.
No, I couldn't...
I've got this. Go
drink some tea.
Are you okay with not helping?
You asked her over, so if you leave
her alone, she's gonna hate you.
Wh-Why are you reading
so far into this, you idiot?
And I didn't invite her over!
Besides, I don't really
care if Tohsaka hates me.
Huh? Where's Tohsaka?
I believe she went
out into the courtyard.
The courtyard?
Tohsaka?
I like the magic field here.
Unlike the one at my house, you
can sense human warmth in this one.
Care to join me?
What?
I was just curious.
This house is unique.
It occurred to me that maybe
you're better off the way you are.
A hopeless amateur, you mean?
I didn't mean it that way,
but maybe that's exactly it.
I don't know what Emiya
Kiritsugu was like as a mage,
but this estate is
incredibly laid-back.
For a mage's
workshop, it's quite open.
It's like you're welcome
to come and go freely.
It isn't like that
at your place?
No, it isn't.
It tries to keep people out, but
once you're in, it doesn't let you leave.
At times, I think it's messed up,
but it isn't something I can change.
Personally, I like
it the way it is.
This personality of mine is probably
why I was chosen as the heir.
Was it hard for you?
Training to be a mage?
Sorry to say, but I
never had much trouble.
Plus, learning
new things was fun.
Didn't I just tell you?
That's how I'm wired.
So if you're worried
about me, don't be.
Okay.
So why do you go to school?
If you're going to live a mage's
life, isn't it sort of pointless?
It may be somewhat of a
detour, but it's not pointless.
It's fun to be a student.
And at heart, having
fun's what I live for.
Succeeding my father is my duty,
but I wouldn't do
it if I didn't enjoy it.
That's even why I partnered with
you. Because you're fun to be around.
I see.
Well, I'm glad
you're having fun.
Thanks.
And? It's been fun
for you too, right?
Why aren't you saying anything?
Well, I just...
Give me a straight
answer, Emiya-kun.
Because I might have
completely misunderstood you.
Well... I guess I never
thought of mage training as fun.
Or even magic itself.
But if the people around
me were happy, I was happy.
So I figured if I studied magic, I might
be able to help someone someday.
I wanted to be a champion
of justice, just like Kiritsugu.
That's why I did it.
Anyway, that's my reason.
So what are you saying? You
didn't study magic for yourself?
I didn't?
I mean, it makes me happy
to be useful to others, so...
No, listen here! That's just
being happy, not having fun!
Look, what I'm asking is
if you personally enjoy it.
I don't care about other people.
I'm asking if there's anything
about magic that you consider fun!
I don't know if I
personally enjoy it.
I guess I feel like I
don't have the right
to ask for more than
I've been given already.
Hey!
Give me a straight answer!
Well... I suppose I don't.
Man, this ticks me off!
So basically,
you're always worrying about
others but never focusing on yourself!
Whoa, hey...
Shut up! No talking back!
I always thought you were similar,
but I never imagined you were this alike!
Calm down, Tohsaka.
I don't understand
why you're so angry.
That's exactly why I'm angry!
All right. That settles it.
Tomorrow, I'll make
you admit defeat!
You're going to go back
to chasing me around?
You bet!
I'll give you a taste of something
special I've been saving!
Hey, Tohsaka!
You're going home, right?
I'll walk you.
Tohsaka!
Enough with the
"Tohsaka, Tohsaka"!
Tohsaka, what are you wearing?
I spoke to Archer and had
him bring me an overnight bag.
Huh?
I got Fujimura-sensei's
permission, so it's fine.
I'll use the guest
room on the right.
Trace on.
Tracing fundamental structure.
Reinforcing
auxiliary components.
More magic training tonight?
Yeah. Kiritsugu taught
me to never miss a day.
But I guess that was the only
thing I really learned from him.
Only that?
He taught you nothing of the wisdom
or behavior expected of mages?
Nah. After all,
despite being my teacher, he
wasn't much of a mage himself.
He was a poor
excuse for an adult.
He'd say that if you
were going to enjoy
something, you should
enjoy it to the fullest,
and then he'd play
around like a kid.
I understand. You enjoyed
having such a master, didn't you?
Yeah. I looked up to him.
He was carefree and
not at all mage-like,
but to me, Kiritsugu
was a true magician.
Shirou.
What is wrong
with your left side?
You noticed?
Yes.
It's just a little numb.
It isn't slowing me down at all.
Is the cause what I think it is?
Yeah, I think it's a reaction to
the projection magic I did last night.
Is your body still half-numb?
Archer.
That's hardly surprising.
What do you want, Archer?
I thought we had a
non-aggression pact.
Stop right there.
If you come any closer, I hope you're
prepared to face the consequences.
Wait, Saber. He
doesn't want to fight.
But...
It's okay.
What do you want, Archer?
Knowing you, I'm guessing you
didn't just drop by to say hello.
Rin told me that you performed
a projection, and it really is true.
You have no sensation
in half your body, and your
center of gravity is seven
centimeters off, correct?
I may be able to assist you.
You're fortunate.
I expected to see necrosis,
but you've simply opened
something that was once closed.
I've opened something
that was once closed?
The circuits you were meant to use from the
beginning had grown dormant from neglect.
The numbness is only temporary.
By suddenly flooding circuits you
never used with mana at full power,
you sent them into
a state of shock.
This means that the circuits
have returned to an active state.
That should do it.
You'll recover in a few days.
When you can
move properly again,
you'll find yourself a
better mage than before.
You certainly know a
lot about this, Archer.
I went through
something similar.
At first, I lost the
use of one arm.
Wait.
What?
I want to ask you something.
"Let your ideals drag
you to your death."
What did you mean by that?
It seems self-explanatory.
There's nothing to add.
Then what the hell
are you fighting for?
That's obvious. I fight
for myself—simple as that.
Just for yourself?
That's right.
If you desire to fulfill your
ideal of nobody getting hurt,
then so be it.
But only if that
desire is truly yours.
If you fight of
your own free will,
you bring the
consequences upon yourself.
Accepting them is
a part of that ideal.
But if that desire was
borrowed from another,
the ideals you uphold
are mere fantasies.
One must have a
reason for fighting.
But that reason must
never be an ideal.
If you fight for an ideal,
you can only save ideals.
And that means
you can't help others.
All reasons to fight
involve saving something.
Or at the very least, yours
does. Is that right, Emiya Shirou?
But salvation by the hands
of another is not salvation.
Such salvation is like money.
When used, it passes
into another's hands.
It's true that you can probably
achieve your desire to save others.
But you have no
desire to save yourself.
You will repeat the
cycle until you die, still
clinging to ideals
that are not your own.
That is why your
ideals are meaningless.
Nothing comes of helping others.
In the end, you can save
neither others nor yourself.
A lie of a life.
You're wrong.
That isn't true.
We didn't understand anything
My left hand groped for
things that vanished to my touch
A moral conflict
stays your hand
and tricks you
out of your future
I don't know how
to protect anyone,
and my ideals might
well be pointless,
but I want to live my life
The past repeats before my eyes
Here I will trust the me
that now stands with you
Until my dream
crumbles and withers,
I hope you will carve
out paradise with me
Fight your fate
You don't have to go to
such extremes to help others!
You truly are a foolish child!
You still have no stomach
for brutality, do you?
I promised myself that I'd
fight to stop people like you.
Run, Shirou!
The Final Decision
Next Time